Plumly mss., 1973-2000 LMC 2552
Lilly Library
Plumly mss.
1973-2000
Lilly Library
Plumly, Stanley
Matthews, William, 1942-1997
LMC 2552
1 Box 1 standard
The Plumly mss., 1973-2000, consist of correspondence between poets William Matthews and Stanley Plumly as well as related materials.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase: 2007
Biographical Note
Stanley Plumly, 1939-, is a poet, professor of English, and director of University of Maryland – College Park's creative writing program.
William Proctor Matthews, III, was born November 11, 1942, in Cincinnati, Ohio. He received his B.A. degree from Yale University in 1965 and his M.A. degree from the University of North Carolina Chapel Hill in 1966. In 1963, he married Marie Harris, an author and poet, whose papers are also housed at the Lilly Library. They have two sons, William IV and Sebastian. The marriage ended in divorce in 1974. In the 1960s and early 1970s, Matthews co-edited the magazine Lillabulero. Matthews also served as the vice-president of the board of directors of the Associated Writers Program as well as chairman of the literature panel of the National Endowment for the Arts. At the time of his death, on November 12, 1997, he was a professor of English and director of the creative writing program at City College of New York. In 1997, he was a recipient of the Ruth Lilly Poetry Prize.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence from William Matthews to Stanley Plumly, as well as some correspondence from Matthews and Plumly to others. Also present is an issue of The Ohioana Quarterly containing a review of a tribute to William Matthew.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series: I. Correspondence and II. Printed Material. Materials in Correspondence are arranged chronologically.
Related Materials
See Matthews, W. mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
- Correspondence
  - 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - 1975 (Box 1)
  - 1976 (Box 1)
  - 1977 (Box 1)
  - 1978 (Box 1)
  - 1979 (Box 1)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - 1982 (Box 1)
  - 1983 (Box 1)
  - 1984 (Box 1)
  - 1985 (Box 1)
  - 1986 (Box 1)
  - 1987 (Box 1)
  - 1988-1992 (Box 1)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - 1995 (Box 1)
  - 1996 (Box 1)
  - 1997 (Box 1)
  - 1998 (Box 1)
  - 1999 (Box 1)
  - 2000 (Box 1)
  - undated (Box 1)
- Printed Material
  - The Ohioana Quarterly, Vol. XLIX, No. 1, Spring 2006 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes review of Blues for Bill: A Tribute for William Matthews